a weight bench is one of the most useful
pieces of gym equipment since they allow
you to work out your entire body
adjustable weight benches though are
even better in my opinion because they
add even more versatility to your
workouts Rogue makes some of the best
workout equipment available that's no
secret and it's also no exception with
the adjustable bench 3.0 I've been using
this weight bench for quite a while so
today I'm going to break down my
findings for y'all foreign
foreign
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym and today I've
got the Rogue adjustable bench 3.0 N4
review in this video I'm going to tell
you everything that you need to know
about this weight bench from the price
and the features the pros and the cons
and of course who should or maybe should
not buy this weight bench but before I
get going we've reviewed a whole lot of
weight benches on barbin.com and if you
want to browse our best list just go
ahead and Google barbend best weight
benches and you can find out for
yourself which one takes home that
number one spot
okay so what do I like about the ab 3.0
well it's adjustable you have 10
different back pad adjustments to go
along with three different seat pad
adjustments it's made from 11 gauge
steel which is pretty much the best
quality you could ask for in your home
gym it's also what you're going to find
in most professional gym settings so
that's really nice as well a handle and
a set of wheels are going to make it
really easy to move it around plus you
can store it vertically to create more
space
foreign
okay so let's talk about a couple cons
you might experience with the ab 3.0 and
let's talk about the money first it's
priced right around 600 bucks and that's
obviously not cheap now it is a premium
quality product with that 11 gauge steel
I was just talking about so you know
you're paying for that quality
but you know there's other way benches
out there that have the exact same
features and they're going to be a
couple hundred dollars cheaper so if
you're not coming close to that max
weight capacity which is going to be
around a thousand pounds I'd suggest
saving some money and going after one of
those cheaper options the back pad is
only 11 inches wide so if you have a
really broad back you know might not be
too crazy about that now for me
personally it's fine you know I don't
really need anything that's much wider
than that but there are people out there
that are going to need that and this
also is not compatible you know with a
wider back pad you can't change it out
so if that's something you're looking
for you know definitely keep looking and
this also is not an FID bench which
stands for flat incline and decline so
this cannot be put in the decline
position now if you want to work in some
decline bench presses
can't really do that here you know you
might be able to stack some weight
plates underneath the foot up here on
the front but that can be a little
tricky and you don't have anywhere to
put your legs so if that's something you
want to do then you definitely are going
to want to look elsewhere
[Music]
all right so let's talk a little bit
more about the pricing with the ab 3.0
the one we have right here is listed
right around six hundred dollars but
once you tack on your shipping and taxes
well you're spending over 700 now
obviously ours is red it's also
available in black and blue but you can
also swap out your adjustment rails from
being black like we have to stainless
steel now that's obviously going to cost
you more money so that model is going to
start right around seven hundred dollars
and it's gonna be over 800 once you tack
on shipping and taxes now the AV 3.0 is
not compatible with a wider back PAD as
I mentioned but you can swap it out for
a premium padding that's going to be an
additional 160 or so so potentially you
could be spending around 900 to a
thousand dollars just on this weight
bench okay so obviously you're gonna be
spending a pretty penny on this weight
bench especially compared to some of
those cheaper options on the market but
this one's in it for the long haul you
know the ab be 3.0 once again is made
from 11 gauge steel so it's super
durable it's super sturdy it's got a
high weight capacity
it's probably going to last you a
lifetime so that might make it worth it
for a lot of you watching now if y'all
know anything about me I am a big
advocate for financing a purchase such
as this one whenever you have the
ability to do so so Rogue is going to
allow you to either use a firm or pay
later from PayPal now a firm they're
going to run a soft credit check on you
and however much you're going to pay
monthly will depend on your credit score
but if you were decide to go with pay
later from PayPal you have the option of
either making four interest-free
payments of around 175 dollars or you
can pay around 35 bucks a month for two
years until you pay this bad boy off
[Music]
foreign
okay so let's talk about the build now
with the ab 3.0
this bad boy weighs a hefty 125 pounds
and I promise you're gonna feel that
when you go to move it around it doesn't
necessarily look like it at first glance
but trust me that's how much it weighs
it's made from 11 gauge steel I've said
that a couple times now I'm pretty
positive you're going to hear me say it
again before this video is over that's
professional quality you know you're
gonna find that in a professional gym
setting so you really can't ask for
better quality in your own personal gym
the vinyl padding is pretty firm it's
going to be really nice give you some
solid support for bench press but it's
not too firm to where it's uncomfortable
for you to lay on so a little bit of
Best of Both Worlds with that so that's
pretty nice the back pad's 11 inches
wide now for me personally I said it
earlier like that's okay for me you know
but there's other people out there that
do in fact want a wider back pad and
unfortunately you cannot Swap this one
out for a wider pad so that'd be nice if
there was some variety or you know maybe
you wanted a thicker backpack so that'd
be pretty cool if you could you know
swap it out but unfortunately you can't
do that right now from end to end it's a
little over four and a half feet long
and including the rear foot it's just
over two feet wide
[Music]
all right now let's talk about the
features that you'll find with the ab
3.0 I really like how this front foot is
relatively small it's going to give you
a lot of foot space on either side of it
that way you can get your optimal foot
placement as well as optimal foot drive
as you go to do your shoulder presses
maybe a bench press whatever it may be
that's really nice you know a lot of
times benches
foot kind of extends out to the side and
that can kind of get in the way a little
bit and that's just not really fun now
you do have a gap right here between the
seat and the back Pad but it's only one
inch Gap that's not bad you know it
doesn't feel too annoying on my lower
back and plus you know there's some
instances some angles you're going to
position everything where there's no Gap
whatsoever so that's really nice you
have a laser cut degree markings for
your backpack as well as your seat pad
that way you always know the exact angle
everything is positioned at plus I
already said it earlier you know you do
have 10 different adjustments for the
back pad and three for the seat pad so
that's really nice as well there's
rubber that's underneath the front and
rear feet it's going to add to the
stability so if you do any step UPS or
really anything where you know you're
stepping on here your body weight's on
here it's not going to topple over on
you so that's really cool as well a
handle and a set of wheels is going to
make it super easy for you to move it
around your personal gym
gonna need that because once again this
does weigh 125 pounds you also have a
vertical storage stand built in on the
back side of the bench right here so
that way you know you can store it
vertically and create more space in your
gym and you know once again you know
ours obviously is red also available in
blue and black and you have the option
of swapping out your black adjustment
rails for stainless steel
all right guys let's go and do a quick
walk around with this weight bench now I
want to highlight the padding first once
again this back pad's only 11 inches
wide as I mentioned it's great for
somebody like myself but if you do have
a really broad back you might have a
little bit of difficulty with this bench
right here but I will say the padding
itself it's nice and firm for your
workouts it's also pretty comfortable so
don't worry you're not going to feel
like you're laying on concrete it's
pretty nice to lay on I have to say now
as far as the adjustments go you have 10
different ones for the back pad three
different ones with a seat pad
it's really nice you do have laser cut
degree markings right here so you always
know exactly what angle you have your
padding positioned to so in terms of
doing that I like grabbing the back pad
and you have a handle on either side of
the adjustment rails right here so just
grab and pull up on the back pad and you
can guide exactly where you want
everything to be positioned
and as I mentioned you know this Gap
right here in between the two paddings
tends to disappear at specific angles
and especially if you raise up on the
seat pad right here as you can see
you know that Gap is gone which is
awesome now I also really love this
front foot design right here it's really
narrow you can get optimal foot drive
for your bench presses there's nothing
interfering with you whatsoever which is
obviously really nice now I also really
like this handle right here super easy
to grab it's not too far underneath the
seat which you often find with a lot of
weight benches that's just going to make
it really easy to move it around your
home gym now before I do that though let
me put this back
foreign
now just simply walk up grab this handle
your wheels are going to make it easy to
move it around your home gym my favorite
thing is this built-in storage stand
because it creates that much more space
in your home gym
[Music]
okay so who should purchase the Rogue
adjustable bench 3.0 well if you're
tight on space but you do still want a
high quality weight bench I think this
is a really good option for you to
consider because it does have that
vertical storage stand that way you can
make the most of your available space
let's double up with the high quality
build you know once again this is made
from 11 gauge steel it is in fact
professional quality
you can't really ask for anything better
for a home gym so it's almost guaranteed
that it's going to last you a lifetime
if you're looking for a weight bench
that you know doesn't have a front foot
that gets in the way of you while you're
lifting and you hate that massive Gap
you often find between the back and seat
pads I think you're really going to
enjoy the design here
not purchase the ab 3.0 well it's pretty
expensive and most of the features here
you're going to find in some other
weight benches that are a couple hundred
dollars cheaper some of them may even
have more features because they're
either compatible with attachments or
they actually include attachments in
their original pricing so if you don't
want to spend 700 on a weight bench I'd
suggest you keep looking and if you want
to incorporate some decline bench
presses into your workout routine I also
suggest that you keep looking because
you don't have that luxury here with the
ab 3.0 and you know if you participate
in weightlifting competitions you
probably don't have much of a need for
an adjustable weight bench plus AB 3.0
does not meet the competition height
standards all right well that's a wrap
for today's review over the Rogue
adjustable bench 3.0 I think this is a
solid weight bench that you should
consider adding to your home gym it's
made from 11 gauge steel you have a lot
of adjustments for you to work with and
storage is also made easy since it can
be stored vertically it is pretty
expensive though and it's not an FID
bench so you won't be able to work in
any decline bench presses thanks for
watching everybody I hope this video was
really helpful that I was able to answer
any questions that you may have about
the ab 3.0 as always stay tuned for my
next review but for now head over to
barbin.com and you can read more about
this weight bench just search bar Bend
Rogue adjustable bench 3.0 review and
you'll find everything I talked about
here today I'll see y'all next time
[Music]
thank you